Hello everyone.
大家好
My name is Kevin Streeter,
我叫Kevin Streeter
and I'm here to talk about some of the challenges that exist
下面我来谈一谈将桌面级创作应用
bringing desktop class creative applications to the web.
带到web上的一些挑战
In this talk, we'll begin with a broad summary
在这次演讲中 我们将首先
of the many technical areas we need to work through
对用来创建强大创作工具的许多技术领域
to create powerful creative tools.
进行概括总结
Then we will dive into a few selected topics to get a better
然后 我们将深入探讨一些选定的主题
feel for the kind of capabilities we need from the web
更好地了解需要从网页中获得什么能力
to make it all possible.
来实现这一切
Let's get started. slide-2
我们开始吧 slide-2
Slide one.
第一张幻灯片
Creators are accustomed to having the full power
创作者们已经习惯于轻松使用
of desktop class hardware at their fingertips.
桌面级硬件的全部力量
How can we build applications that have the same level
我们怎样才能建立
of performance and expressivity,
具有同等水平的性能和表现力的应用
but also having all the benefits of a web based experience? 18-p
同时又兼具基于网页体验的所有好处呢 18-p
Here are some of the ways that applications take advantage
以下是一些应用程序
of traditional desktop platforms. 20-p
利用传统桌面平台的方法 20-p
These applications have full access to 64-bit CPUs
这些应用程序可以完全访问64位CPU
and performance or instruction sets such as AVX. 22-p
以及性能或指令集 如AVX 22-p
They have access to large amounts of memory. 23-p
它们可以访问大量的内存 23-p
They have full access to disk hardware
可以完全访问磁盘硬件
and the local file system. 25-p
和本地文件系统 25-p
They use low level APIs for performance and efficiency. 26-p
它们使用底层API来提高性能和效率 26-p
They have end to end support for color management
它们对色彩管理和色彩空间有端到端的支持
and color spaces that allow for wide color gamuts
可以实现宽色域
and high dynamic range. 29-p
和高动态范围 29-p
Desktop software has access to input hardware,
桌面软件可以使用硬件输入设备
such as styluses, pens, and other devices. 31-p
如手写笔 触笔和其他设备 31-p
They have access to modern media decoding and encoding,
它们可以使用现代媒体解码和编码
particularly video encoding and decoding. 33-p
特别是视频编码和解码 33-p
They have access to modern GPU pipelines
它们可以使用现代GPU管线
that support both graphics and compute. 35-p
同时支持图形和计算 35-p
And finally, they have access to the kind of quality
最后 它可以提供高质量的用户体验
of experience capabilities such as clipboards,
如剪贴板 无障碍功能和其他功能
accessibilities and other things that really
这些都使得创作工具
make a tool work for the creative professional. slide-3
能真正为专业创作者服务 slide-3
Slide two.
第二张幻灯片
The first area that we're going to dive deeper into
我们要深入探讨的第一个领域
is the use of WebAssembly. 42-p
是WebAssembly的使用 42-p
Creative media tools tend to use a mix
媒体创作工具往往会混合使用
of new and existing media processing code.
新式和现有的媒体处理代码
The existing code is typically written in C++.
现有的代码通常是用C++编写的
This code tends to be a mix of compute
这种代码往往是
intensive and memory intensive operations.
计算密集型和内存密集型操作的混合
Importantly, not all of this code can simply
重要的是 并非所有这些代码
be ported to a GPU. 49-p
都可以简单地移植到GPU上 49-p
Sometimes that's because we haven't really found
有时 这是因为我们还没有真正找到
a good GPU-based solution for the operation,
一个基于GPU的好的解决方案
but frequently it's also because we have working code
但主要是因为我们有能够正常运行的代码
and we'd really like to continue to use it. 53-p
我们会倾向于继续使用它 53-p
These code bases have been heavily optimized over time,
随着时间推移 这些代码库已经被大量优化
and they've been optimized in a couple of different ways.
经历了多种不同的优化方式
They've been optimized to take advantage
它们在经过优化后可以
of 64-bit processing,
利用64位处理
and they've also been optimized to take advantage
它们在经历优化后能利用
of SIMD instruction sets that are present
大多数桌面级硬件中存在的
on most desktop class hardware. 60-p
SIMD指令集 60-p
If we want to do these types of things on the web,
如果我们想在web上实现这类功能
we've got a few challenges today.
如今还面临着几项挑战
One is that in-browser support
其一是如今的浏览器中
for WebAssembly today is all 32-bit.
对WebAssembly的支持都是32位的
That not only limits the processing capabilities,
这不仅限制了处理能力
but it also limits the total amount of memory
而且还限制了我们可以使用的
that we have access to. 67-p
内存总量 67-p
SIMD is not currently supported in most browsers.
目前大多数浏览器都不支持SIMD指令集
There are some proposals around SIMD operations,
有一些围绕着SIMD执行的技术提案
and there are support for that in some browsers,
在一些浏览器中也有支持
but it's still very early
但就可用性而言
in terms of availability of that capability. 72-p
它仍然处在非常早期的阶段 72-p
One important aspect of this
其中一个重要的方面是
is that the SIMD proposals that are currently
目前正在研究的SIMD技术提案
being investigated really do emphasize
确实强调了
portability over performance.
可移植性而不是性能
And what this means is that we no longer really have access
这意味着我们不再能够
to the lowest level of instruction sets,
访问到最底层的指令集
and that does have an impact on overall performance. slide-4
而这确实对整体性能产生了影响 slide-4
Slide three.
第三张幻灯片
The next important area I'd like to discuss is color. 81-p
我想讨论的下一个重要领域是色彩 81-p
Color management, wide color gamut,
色彩管理 宽色域
and high dynamic range capabilities
和高动态范围功能
are critical for pro media production.
对专业媒体制作至关重要
This is true regardless of the type of media,
不管是什么类型的媒体
whether it's video photography or print. 86-p
无论是视频摄影还是印刷品 都是如此 86-p
Consumer devices such as phones and tablets
消费类设备如手机和平板电脑
increasingly support wide color gamut
越来越多地支持宽色域和高动态范围
and high dynamic range, making the ability
使得为这些设备
to deliver correct color
提供显示正确色彩的能力
to these devices even more important. 91-p
变得更加重要 91-p
It's critical to keep in mind
要记住
that color is an end-to-end problem
色彩是一个端到端的问题
and that we have to solve for that
我们必须在系统的所有方面
across all aspects of the system.
解决这个问题
That includes formats, pixel processing, and rendering. 96-p
这包括格式 像素处理和渲染 96-p
Now, today, standards such as CSS 4
如今 像CSS4这样的标准
are helping make it possible
正在帮助实现
to support extended color spaces,
对扩展色彩空间的支持
but this isn't supported broadly in all browsers today. 100-p
但这并没有在如今的所有浏览器中得到广泛支持 100-p
Also these color management capabilities are not supported
同时 这些色彩管理能力
by all web modules.
也并非被所有的web组件所支持
For example, today there isn't really a way
例如 到现在还没有一个真正的解决办法
to ensure that WebGL is going to display
来确保WebGL能够
wide color gamut content correctly. 105-p
正确地显示宽色域的内容 105-p
Last, it's really important to note that different
最后 需要注意的是不同行业
industries have their own standards around color.
都有自己的色彩标准 这一点非常重要
What that means is that the web platform
这意味着 如果我们想
needs to be inclusive if we want to support
支持创建针对这些行业的工具
the creation of tools that target these industries. slide-5
web平台就需要具有包容性 slide-5
Slide four.
第四张幻灯片
Next let's talk about disks and file systems. 112-p
接下来我们来谈谈磁盘和文件系统 112-p
Desktop creative tools use the local disk heavily and rely
桌面创作工具大量使用本地磁盘
on access to the local file system.
并依赖于对本地文件系统的访问
These tools use disks for variety of reasons.
这些工具会出于各种原因使用磁盘
They use them to store documents and projects.
可能是用来存储文件和项目
They use them for importing and exporting content
用来导入和导出
in and out of the application,
应用程序中的内容
and they use them for scratch space and for caching. 119-p
也可能用来作为暂存空间和缓存 119-p
These tools have been optimized for disk I/O very carefully,
这些工具对磁盘数据传输做了很好的优化
and they try to minimize both the total number of I/O
它们试图将数据传输操作的总数
operations and the total amount of data transferred. 122-p
和传输的数据总量都降到最低 122-p
Today's browser-based file access
如今的基于浏览器的文件访问
doesn't really give write access to the local file system.
并没有真正给予本地文件系统的写入权限
And the APIs are fairly high level, meaning it's hard to
而且API的层级相当高 这意味着
ensure that the I/O is optimal. 126-p
很难确保数据传输处于最佳状态 126-p
Current proposals such as Origin Private File System
目前有一些提案 像域私有文件系统
are promising, but need to allow for efficient
非常有希望 但需要允许
import and export with a host file system. 129-p
与主机文件系统的高效导入和导出 129-p
In the end, many low level capabilities
最后 许多底层能力
don't really have an analog in the web platform.
在网页平台上并没有真正模拟实现
For example, there's no support for sparse files
例如 没有对稀疏文件
or zero copy file I/O. slide-6
或零拷贝文件传输的支持 slide-6
Slide five.
第五张幻灯片
The last topic I'd like to dive deeper on
我想深入探讨的最后一个话题
is hardware encoding and decoding of media. 136-p
是媒体的硬件编解码 136-p
Pro media production tools often use more specialized
与典型的消费者应用相比
media formats than in a typical consumer application.
专业媒体制作工具通常使用更多专业媒体格式
For example, a photography tool will use formats
例如 摄影工具会使用像TIFF
like TIFF, JPEG 2000, and a variety
和JPEG 2000
of different raw image formats.
以及各种不同的原始图像格式
Similarly, video tools will use things
同样 视频处理工具会使用
like REDCODE, ARRIRAW, or ProRes. 143-p
像REDCODE ARRIRAW或ProRes这类的格式 143-p
Now for imaging applications,
对于图像处理应用
we can get away with using WebAssembly
我们可以使用WebAssembly
to do encoding and decoding,
来进行编码和解码
especially if we've tackled some of the performance issues
特别是如果我们已经解决了
that we spoke about earlier in the talk.
刚才谈到的一些性能问题
But video is much harder since maintaining
但视频处理就困难多了
good frame rates during playback, scrubbing,
因为在播放 拖进度条和其他动作中
and other aspects of authoring are really, really important. 151-p
保持良好的帧率是非常非常重要的 151-p
Now today, the ability to get hardware accelerated video
如今 网页中的视频元素已经可以提供
is present in the web through the video element,
硬件加速视频的能力
and soon we'll have access through an API
而且WebCodecs等API
such as WebCodecs.
也会陆续提供这一功能
But a problem with these APIs is that they only work
但这些API的一个问题是
with mainstream consumer-oriented formats
它们只适用于主流的消费者编码格式
like AVC and VP8 and VP9. 158-p
如AVC VP8和VP9 158-p
Now, unfortunately there is an unavoidable challenge
但媒体编解码器有一个不可避免的挑战
with media codecs, is that many of them
那就是大多数编解码器
are encumbered by intellectual property issues,
都受到知识产权问题的困扰
making it much harder to ensure they are available
这使得确保它们在所有设备上都可用
on all devices all the time. 163-p
变得更加困难 163-p
So what we may need here is some way to access pluggable
因此 可能我们所需要的是访问可插拔
or modular hardware acceleration capabilities,
或模块化硬件加速能力的方法
so when this capability is present on a device,
当某种设备能够提供这类功能时
the application can get access to it. slide-7
应用程序可以访问它 slide-7
Last slide.
最后一张幻灯片
I hope you enjoyed this talk.
我希望你喜欢这次演讲
I'd like to give a quick thank you to all the folks
我想向所有帮助我准备这些材料的
at Adobe that helped me prepare this material.
Adobe公司员工表示感谢
And in particular, I'd like to thank
我想特别感谢
Sean Voisen for his insights. slide-8
Sean Voisen提供的宝贵见解 slide-8
See you at the workshop.
我们研讨会上见